A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Personal and Professional papers FA965
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Personal and professional papers
  - Johns Hopkins University, Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1953-1957
    - OSRD, NDRC, JF, Optical Instruments, 1944 July 25 (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - OSRD, NDRC, JF, Tropical Deterioration Administrative Committee, 1945 October 31 (Box 123, Folder 17)
    - OSRD, NDRC, JF, Tropical Deterioration Administrative Committee, 1945 October 31 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - OSRD, Oxygen Candle Apparatus for Use in Aircraft, 1946 January (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - OSRD, NDRC, Oximeters for Use in Aircraft, 1946 January (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - OSRD, Committee on Medical Research, 1942-1945 (Box 123, Folder 21)
    - OSRD, Committee on Aviation Medicine, 1945 (Box 123, Folder 22)
    - OSRD, NRC, Reports, 1942-1943 (Box 123, Folder 23)
    - OSRD, NRC, JF, Reports, 1942-1945 (Box 123, Folder 24)
    - OSRD, JF, Reports, 1944 (Box 123, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Special Studies Project, 1956-1958
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF), Special Studies Project, 1956 December 20 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF), Special Studies Project, 1956 December 20 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, 1956 December 20 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Minutes, 1957 March 29 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Minutes, 1957 March 29 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Overall Panel, 1957-1959 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Overall Panel, 1957-1959 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Subpanel II, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Subpanel II, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Subpanel II, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project, Panel II Report, 1958 (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project Report, Subpanel IV, 1958 June 5 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project Report, Subpanel IV, 1958 June 5 (Box 124, Folder 13)
    - RBF, Special Studies Project Report, Subpanel IV, 1958 June 5 (Box 124, Folder 14)
  - NSF, Publications, 1955-1964
    - National Science Foundation (NSF), Federal Grants and Contracts for Unclassified Research in the Physical Sciences, 1955 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - NSF, Basic Research, a National Resource, 1957 August 16 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - NSF, Funds for Research and Development in Industry, 1957 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - NSF, Government-University Relationships, 1958 April (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - NSF, Federal Grants and Contracts for Unclassified Research in the Physical Sciences, 1958 April (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - NSF, Scientific Activities in Six State Governments, 1958 June (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - NSF, Funds for Scientific Activities in the Federal Government, 1958 July (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - NSF, Federal Grants and Contracts for Unclassified Research in the Life Sciences, 1958 September (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - NSF, Scientists and Engineers in the Federal Government, 1958 October (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - NSF, Information for Scientists, 1958 November (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - NSF, Colleges and Universities, Expenditures and Manpower, 1958 December (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - NSF, Federal Funds for Science, 1958 (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - NSF, Scientific Manpower, 1958 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - NSF, Science Information News, 1959 (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - NSF, Federal Grants for Science, 1959 (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - NSF, Science and Engineering in American Industry, 1959 (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - NSF, Science Information News, 1959 December-1960 May (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - NSF, A Study of Scientific and Technical Manpower, 1960 January (Box 125, Folder 18)
    - NSF, Supplement to Nonconventional Technical Info Systems in Current Use, 1960 March (Box 125, Folder 19)
    - NSF, Kitt Peak National Observatory, 1960 May (Box 125, Folder 20)
    - NSF, Federal Funds for Science IX, 1960 December (Box 125, Folder 21)
    - NSF, Statistical Handbook of Science Education, 1960 (Box 125, Folder 22)
    - NSF, Scientific Manpower, 1960 (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - NSF, Funds for Research and Development in Industry - 1958, 1961 May (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - NSF, Nonprofit Organizations, Expenditures and Manpower - 1957, 1961 May (Box 125, Folder 25)
    - NSF, Women in Scientific Careers, 1961 July (Box 125, Folder 26)
    - NSF, Scientific Information Activities of Federal Agencies, 1961 November-December (Box 125, Folder 27)
    - NSF, Federal Funds For Science X, 1961 December (Box 125, Folder 28)
    - NSF, Investing in Scientific Progress, 1961 (Box 125, Folder 29)
    - NSF, Survey of Copyrighted Material Reproduction Practices in Scientific and Technical Fields, 1962 March (Box 125, Folder 30)
    - NSF, Scientific Information Activities of Federal Agencies, 1962 September-October (Box 125, Folder 31)
    - NSF, Scientific Information News, 1962 October-November (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - NSF, Colleges and Universities, Expenditures and Manpower - 1958, 1962 December (Box 125, Folder 33)
    - NSF, Scientific Manpower From Abroad, 1962 (Box 125, Folder 34)
    - NSF, Scientific Personnel and Education, 1962 (Box 125, Folder 35)
    - NSF, Federal Funds for Science XI, 1963 January (Box 125, Folder 36)
    - NSF, Research and Development in Industry - 1960, 1963 January (Box 125, Folder 37)
    - NSF, Manpower Report of the President, 1963 March (Box 125, Folder 38)
    - NSF, A National Plan for Science Abstracting and Indexing Service, 1963 March (Box 125, Folder 39)
    - NSF, Science for Information News, 1963 June-September (Box 125, Folder 40)
    - NSF, Two Years After the College Degree, 1963 (Box 125, Folder 41)
    - NSF, Weather Modification, 1963 June (Box 125, Folder 42)
    - NSF, Industrial R and D Funds in Relation to Other Economic Variables, 1964 October (Box 125, Folder 43)
    - NSF, Scientific and Technical Manpower Resources, 1964 November (Box 125, Folder 44)
    - NSF, Weather Modification, 1964 December (Box 125, Folder 45)
    - NSF, Scientific and Technical Personnel in the Federal Government, 1964 December (Box 125, Folder 46)
    - NSF, Scientists and Engineers in Colleges and Universities, 1964 December (Box 125, Folder 47)
  - Reprints on Axonal Flow, Lantern Slides, Nerve Regeneration Bibliography, 1930-1973
    - Reprints on Axonal Flow, 1930-1973 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Lantern Slides (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Nerve Regeneration Bibliography (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Detlev Wulf Bronk, Praeses et Curatores Universitatis Princetoniensis, Sc.D, 1947 February 22; 14½ × 17 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania Military College, Sc.D, 1965 June 6; 23½ × 17½ (Box 127, Folder 2A)
    - Hamilton College, Sc.D, 1961 June 4; 18½ × 14½ (Box 127, Folder 3A)
    - Citation & Commencement (Box 127, Folder 3C)
    - Curatores Collegii Lafayettensis, LLD, 1958 June 6; 19¾ × 16 (Box 127, Folder 4A)
    - Curatores Yeshivae Universitatis, LHD, 1965 November 1; 16½ × 14 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - University of Cincinnati, Eng. D., 1951 June 8; 13 × 17 (Box 127, Folder 6A)
    - University of CA - La Jolla, LL.D., 1959 March 26; 17 × 12 (Box 127, Folder 7A)
    - Curatores Collegii Ursini, LHD, 1974 June 2; 17 × 13 (Box 127, Folder 8A)
    - American Philosophical Society, Election to Membership, 1934 April 20; 17 × 12 (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - The American Neurological Association, Election to Associate Membership, 1933 May 9 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Universitas Bucknellensis, LHD, 1957; 21½ × 17 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - The University of the State of New York, Sc.D., 1960 May 21; Has color stains on the outside; 20 × 15¾ (Box 127, Folder 12A)
    - Alpha Mu Pi Omega, Election to Membership, 1938 April 26; 16½ × 13 (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - Universitatis Pennsylvaniensis, LL.D, 1949 June 15; 23 × 19¼ (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - Regia Academia Scientiarum Sueccica, Doktorem Clarissimum, 1958 March 12; 12½ × 19½ (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - Hahnemanniamum Medicinae Collegium, LL.D, 1959 June 3; 21½ × 16½ (Box 127, Folder 16A)
    - Color copy of a portrait of Benjamin Franklin from the Benjamin Franklin Institute (Box 127, Folder 17A)
    - Fifteenth Annual Priestly Lecturer - Pennsylvania State College, 1941 March 3-7; 12 × 16 (Box 127, Folder 18)
    - University of Maryland, Sc.D., 1962 June 9; 17 × 14 (Box 127, Folder 19A)
    - Reed College, LL.D., 1957 April 7; 12 × 9 (Box 127, Folder 20A)
    - Citation (Box 127, Folder 20B)
    - Curatores Collegii Bostoniensis S.J, Sc.D, 1962 June 11; 19 × 15 (Box 127, Folder 21A)
    - Collegii Kenyonensis, Sc.D, 1958 June 2; 20½ × 16¾ (Box 127, Folder 22A)
    - The Franklin Institute, Franklin Medal Award, 1961 October 18; 12½ × 17¾ (Box 127, Folder 23A)
    - Ribbon: Harvard Red, White & Gold (Box 128, Folder 2B)
    - Ribbon: Blue & Gold (Box 129, Folder 3B)
    - Ribbon: Burgundy (Box 130, Folder 4B)
    - Ribbon: Black & Red (Box 131, Folder 6B)
    - Ribbon: Blue & Gold (Box 132, Folder 7B)
    - Ribbon: Red, Black & Gold (Box 133, Folder 8B)
    - Ribbon: purple & gold (Box 134, Folder 12B)
    - Ribbon: Blue & Gold (Box 135, Folder 16B)
    - Ribbon: Gold & Black (Box 136, Folder 19B)
    - Ribbon: Maroon & Gold (Box 137, Folder 21B)
    - Ribbon: purple (Box 138, Folder 22B)
    - Ribbon: white (Box 139, Folder 23B)
    - Universidade do Brasil, Doctor Honoris Causa, 1960 November 10; 22½ × 15½ (Box 140, Folder 24)
    - Miami University Oxford, Ohio, LL.D., 1958 June 9; 12 × 17 (Box 140, Folder 25A)
    - Second Session of the General Conference of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization. Appointment as Alternate Representative, 1947 October 7; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26A)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics. Appointment to membership, 1948 June 25; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26B)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics. Appointment to Membership, 1950 November 14; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26C)
    - National Science Board, National Science Foundation. Appointment to Membership, 1950 November 4; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26)
    - National Science Board, National Science Foundation. Appointment to Membership, 1952 May 10; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26E)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics. Appointment to Membership, 1955 November 30; 23½ × 19 (Box 140, Folder 26)
    - Senatus Collegii Tuftensis Academias. Litterarum Doctoris, 1959 June 5; 18 × 13½ (Box 140, Folder 27)
    - The Queen's University of Belfast, LL.D., 1952 September 3; 13 × 16 (Box 140, Folder 28A)
    - Ribbon: Red (Box 141, Folder 25B)
    - Ribbon: Dark Green (Box 142, Folder 28B)
    - Karolinska Institute (Stockholm). Honorary MD, 1956 May 30; Ribbon with seal attached to document; 11½ × 18½ (Box 143, Folder 29A)
    - 18K Gold Ring Engraved on Inside [Detlev W. Bronk 30-5-1956], 1956 May 30 (Box 144, Folder 29B)
    - Universitatis Dominae Nostrae a Lacu (Notre Dame), LL.D., 1953 June 7; 19½ × 15¾ (Box 145, Folder 30A)
    - Facsimile of appointment of Joseph Brewster, Jr. to the rank of Ensign in the service of His Majesty King George III's Army, Colony of Connecticut, New England, Hartford, Conn, 1764 May 4; 13½ × 8¾ (Box 145, Folder 31)
    - Collegii Swarthmoriensis, Septimo menis sexti, ScD, 1937; 24½ × 17¾ (Box 145, Folder 32A)
    - The Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, Honorary Membership, 1961 October 18; 12½ × 20 (Box 145, Folder 33)
    - Citation from Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller appointing Dr. Bronk to the Board of Directors of the New York State Science and Technology Foundation. Appointment to Membership, 1964 December 14; 18 × 14½ (Box 145, Folder 34A)
    - Citation from Gov. Nelson A. Rockefeller appointing Dr. Bronk to the Board of Directors of the New York State Science and Technology Foundation, 1965 February 22 (Box 145, Folder 34B)
    - Appointment to Membership, 18 × 14½ (Box 145)
    - Académie Royale de Médecine de Belgique. Appointment as Foreign Honorary Member, 1975 November 22; 18¾ × 14½ (Box 145, Folder 35)
    - Jeffersoniani Medicinae Collegii Philadelphiae, LL.D, 1959 June 22; Gold Foil Medallion Peeling; 20½ × 15½ (Box 145, Folder 36A)
    - Citation from Dwight D. Eisenhower as member of National Science Board, National Science Foundation. Appointment to Member, 1958 July 2; 23 × 19 (Box 145, Folder 37A)
    - Citation from Dwight D. Eisenhower as member of the National Aeronautics & Space Council. Appointment to Member, 1958 September 4; 23 × 19 (Box 145, Folder 37B)
    - Unversitas Torontonensis (University of Toronto), Sc.D., 1953 September 15; 20 × 17 (Box 145, Folder 38A)
    - The Holland Society of New York, Certificate of the Presentation of the Gold Medal, 1961 November 3; 19 × 15 (Box 145, Folder 39)
    - Universitas Rockefellerina, ScD, 1969 June 13; 17½ × 22½ (Box 145, Folder 40A)
    - Universitas Libera Bruxellensis, Doctor Honoris causa, 1963 November 26; 20 × 26 (Box 145, Folder 41A)
    - Catholic University (founded 1425}, Doctor Honoris Causa, 1968 September 20; 21½ × 16½ (Box 145, Folder 42A)
    - Collegii Dartmuthensis, LLD, 1956 June 10; 19 × 15 (Box 145, Folder 43A)
    - National Academy of Sciences, Royal Swedish Academy of Science, Celebration of Centenary of NAS, 12½ × 20½ (Box 145, Folder 44A)
    - University of London, ScD, 1960 March 30; 14½ × 22½ (Box 145, Folder 45A)
    - Ribbon: Burgundy (Box 146, Folder 30B)
    - Ribbon: Red and White (Box 147, Folder 32B)
    - Ribbon: Light Blue & Black (Box 148, Folder 36B)
    - Ribbon: Blue (Box 149, Folder 40B)
    - Citation (Box 150, Folder 4C)
    - Letter to society members (Box 150, Folder 17B)
    - Citation, 1955 (Box 150, Folder 26G)
    - Citation (Box 150, Folder 38B)
    - Citation (Box 150, Folder 43B)
    - Citation (Box 150, Folder 45B)
    - The National Academy of Sciences, Commendation for work as their Foreign Secretary, 13 × 16 (Box 150, Folder 47)
    - The American Society of European Chemists, Commendations for his efforts to promote International Relations, 1959 November 24; 11 × 14 (Box 150, Folder 50)
    - Helen and Detlev Bronk, National Science Board, Coat of Arms given "with gratitude and appreciation" (included on engraved plaque which was attached to the frame), 1964; 13 × 16 (Box 150, Folder 51)
    - Bronk coat-of-arms (Box 150, Folder 51)
    - Shield: Per fess argent and azure (silver and blue), At fess point a demi-sun in splendor issuant or (gold). Wreath: Colors are argent (silver) and azure (blue). Crest: An eagle displayed proper (natural colors) perched on a demi-globe vert (green). Motto: No Cede malis. (Box 150, Folder 51)
    - The Trustees of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute. Naming of the Detlev W. Bronk Bio-Science Laboratory, 15 × 18 (Box 150, Folder 53)
    - War Department, Commendation for Exceptional Civil Service (Box 151, Folder 46)
    - The Golden Age Club, The Golden Jubilee Award (Descendent of the First Settlers of the Bronx), 1964 (Box 152, Folder 48)
    - The President of the United States of America, Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1964 September 14; 15½ × 12½ (Box 153, Folder 52)
    - The Department of the Army, For Patriotic Service as a Scientific Advisor to The Secretary of the Army, 10¾ × 13 (Box 154, Folder 55)
    - Cardboard Casing - Blue (Box 155, Folder 40C)
    - Cardboard Casing - Blue (Box 155, Folder 41B)
    - Leather Casing - Blue (Box 155, Folder 42B)
    - Leather Casing - Dark Green (Box 155, Folder 43C)
    - Leather Casing - Navy Blue (Box 155, Folder 44B)
    - Leather Casing - Red (*Red Paint is peeling) (Box 155, Folder 45C)
    - Photo Album, 1958-1973 (Box 156)
      (some loose photos in separate folder, 1946-1972).
    - Photo Album, 1965-1970 (Box 157)
      (some loose photos in album, not dated).
    - Photo of Detlev Bronk with Eleanor Roosevelt, President of Brandeis University, and Harry Truman, 15½ × 12¼ (Folder 157, Folder 49)
    - Photo of Presidents of John Hopkins - D.W. Bronk, Lincoln Gordon, and Milton Eisenhower, 12 × 10¼ (Box 157, Folder 54)
    - Photo of D.W. Bronk and John F. Kennedy at a Convocation Ceremony (Box 157, Folder 56)